Sidney Laufman Papers
Sidney Laufman Papers
1922-1964
Laufman, Sidney, 1891-
0.5 linear ft.
Artwork reproductions, clippings, printed material, correspondence of the American painter
2744176
Biographical History
Sidney Laufman (1891-1985) was an American painter known for his landscapes, still lifes, and abstractions.
Born in Cleveland, Ohio, Laufman studied at the Art Institute of Chicago and at The Art Students League under Robert Henri. In the 1920s Laufman and his wife relocated to Paris but continued to frequently travel to New York to exhibit works. The two spent the winters in Sarasota, Florida, and eventually permanently relocated there in 1975.
Laufman exhibited prolifically; at the Corcoran 10 times alone. He won the Logan Prize at the AIC twice and the first Altman prize at the National Gallery of Design.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Sidney Laufman Papers consists of artwork reproductions, correspondence, and memorabilia.
Artwork reproductions contains reproductions of Laufman's work in photograph and negative form.
Correspondence contains a single incoming letter and some biographical material.
Memorabilia contains clippings, exhibition material, and a scrapbook.
Arrangement of the Collection
Artwork reproductions is in no particular order. Correspondence is a single item. Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by subject and, when applicable, chronologically within the folder with undated material at the end.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Laufman, Sidney, 1891-; Painters -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Negatives (photographs); Scrapbooks.; Exhibition catalogs.; Magazines (periodicals); Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, 1964.
Inventory
- Artwork reproductions
  - Negatives (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, 1939; 1 item (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings, 1948-1962; undated (Box 1)
  - Critic reviews, undated; typescript (Box 1)
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1922-1963; undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibition invitations, 1927-1964; undated (Box 1)
  - Magazine, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, undated (Oversize 1)
  - Scrapbook (photocopy of above), undated (Box 1)